# SADIA GHANI MALIK

· Cell: (+92) - 331 2844166

· Email: sadiamallick94@gmail.com · LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sadiaghanimalik

· Skype: sadia.mallick8

Team player software engineer, having 5 years of experience in developing robust code for financial businesses that includes back-end services (.Net C#, Dotnet Core), mobile apps (Android/Hybrid), POS applications (Android, C) and web applications (ASP.Net).

# **EXPERIENCE**

JULY. 2019 - PRESENT

# **SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, WEMSOL PVT (LTD.)**

- Develop software design and architecture.
- Improving system architectures for best solutions implementations.
- Designing database architecture and documenting changes and impacts.
- Work closely with team leads and managers to achieve goals.
- Collaborate with internal team to brainstorm and create new products.
- Review and debug code

#### MARCH, 2016 - JUNE, 2019

# **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, WEMSOL PVT (LTD.)**

- Develop software solutions by studying information needs; studying systems flow, work processes; investigating problem areas; following the software development life-cycle.
- Improving system architectures for best solutions implementations.
- Designing database architecture and documenting changes and impacts.
- Work closely with team leads and managers to achieve goals.
- Collaborate with team to brainstorm and create new products.
- Research and implement the optimization and tuning of high-cost SQL Queries.
- Debugging and fixing potential issues and system vulnerabilities.

# **EDUCATION**

#### JANRUARY, 2012 - DECEMBER, 2015

# BACHELORS OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SIR SYED UET, KARACHI

- Merit-based scholarships in each semester for holding positions in each semester.
- On securing first position in Computer Engineering department (CGPA 3.89), awarded with:
  - Gold medal from Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology
  - Gold medal from The Institute of Engineers, Pakistan (IEP)

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

- C#
- Java
- MS SQL
- WCF
- REST Services
- Web service
- Micro services
- Socket Server

- T-SQL
- Windows Services
- Sonar Qube
- New Relic
- OOP
- Layered Architecture
- XSD, XSLT

- TFS
- Gitlab
- Postman
- Dotnet Core
- C language

# **PROJECTS**

**2020 - PRESENT** 

POS ACQUIRING, (ANDROID, C)

Acquiring system for debit and credit transactions on 8210, 8110, 9220 devices.

#### MAIN FEATURES AND INTEGRATIONS

### **ASSOCIATIONS**

#### **SERVICE PROVIDER**

- PayPak Euronet
- UnionPay MasterCard
- Visa

• 1Link

# **2020 - PRESENT**

**KEENU LOYALTY, (ANDROID, C)** 

Provided loyalty programs for merchants on 8210, 8110, 9220 devices.

#### MAIN FEATURES AND INTEGRATIONS

# **FEATURES**

- Sale
- Redemption
- Balance Inquiry
- Settlement

#### 2017 - 2020

# **KEENU WALLET, (.NET, IONIC)**

E-Wallet system that enables users to perform their transactions via wallet such as; Add Money, Funds Transfer, Bill Payments, Scan N Pay, Retail/NFC Payments, Online Payments, Buy Insurance, Buy Tickets.

### MAIN FEATURES AND INTEGRATIONS

#### **FEATURES INTEGRATION**

Bank AL Habib / Meezan bank Cash Deposits / Bank Transfer

Bank AL Habib / Nadra / Meezan bank Biometric

Debit Credit : HBL Cybersource, UPOP

Buy TicketsBuy InsuranceEasy TicketsSmart Choice

Retail NFC / Card Linking : Vaulsys

1 Bill Topup
Push Notifications
Book a Ride
Sms/Email Alerts
Add Money
1 Link, Kuick Pay
One Signal
Uber
EOcean
1Bill, KuickPay

#### **OTHER FEATURES**

- Scan N Pay implemented by scanning Merchant's Static / Dynamic QR Codes.
- Telco's, Vouchers, Utility Bills, Donations are implemented by using Bill Payment System.
- Transactional Rewards and Alerts implemented by using Windows Services.
- Module specific automations implemented by SQL Jobs and Windows Services.
- Socket server implemented for performing retail payments.

#### 2019 - 2020

# FRAUD MONITORING SYSTEM, (.NET)

Real-time transactions pushed by Euronet, PayPak, Vaulsys are monitored by banks in batch wise order.

#### **MAIN FEATURES**

- Insert Transaction Service exposed to Euronet, Vaulsys and PayPak.
- Data monitoring services exposed to Bank Al Habib.

# 2018 - 2020

# **BILL PAYMENT SYSTEM, (.NET)**

Telco's, Vouchers, Bill payments and Donation implemented by integrating Nadra, Novatti, 1Link services.

#### 2016 - 2017

# **SCAN N PAY MOBILE APPLICATION, (ANDROID / .NET)**

In-store payments made via scanning merchant's static / dynamic QR codes. Payments made via fingerprint verification or via Passcode by Keenu Wallet.

#### 2016 - 2017 - BUGS FIXES ONLY

# **ASKARI MOBILE APPLICATION, (.NET / ANDROID)**

User-friendly mobile app allows user to access Askari bank account(s).

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Android Application held in AMI Apex, Janruary, 2015 May, 2015
- Net held in Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology, February, 2014 April, 2014
- Html5 held in Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology, May, 2013 September, 2013